[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 11]
Oh, Xing.
What am I supposed to say to you?
Your heartfelt plea just now
showed your loyalty to our Ministry of Justice.
It was as clear as the sun in the sky,
truly moving.
But to speak like that in front of Lord Lai,
it was far too bold.
That's the
Black Rakshasa.
My Lord.
Yes, Xing,
my heart is still racing from fear.
Do you really think you're
some kind of dominatrix?
Well,
the thing is, even if the Black Rakshasa
encountered demons and evil spirits,
he could
cut out their heart and eat it.
Tell me,
why should we provoke him?
Princess Ying has arrived.
Greetings, Your Highness.
Mrs. Shen, you're wise,
attentive in investigating cases,
and adept at managing the household.
You are truly
a rare female talent.
Our dynasty encourages women to enter officialdom,
allowing women to become generals and ministers.
Madam Grand Commander,
you are indeed a role model in this regard.
Thank you for your kind words, Your Highness.
May I ask the purpose
of your visit today?
Last night, Chen Huo'e came back to life.
This morning,
Lord Lai requested from Her Majesty
the authority to investigate the case.
This case is intricate and complex.
I assume the Ministry of Justice
would prefer not to get entangled in it.
This case
was originally under the jurisdiction of the Imperial Security Bureau.
Now that Lord Lai is reinvestigating,
our Ministry of Justice has no authority to interfere,
nor do we dare to.
However, Yan Xing,
besides being a scribe in the Ministry of Justice,
you are also the wife of the Grand Commander.
Mrs. Shen, I've heard that you
are quite skilled in managing your husband.
If you
could persuade your husband
not to get involved in this case,
and if you could also restrain your own curiosity
and remain a bystander,
I would be willing
to do you a favor.
I would personally request
an imperial decree from Her Majesty
to allow your third sister and Han Shiyuan
to become a married couple.
I am quite busy, you know.
Mrs. Shen, I hope you can give me an answer soon.
Alright?
Xing.
Yan Xing.
You originally had nothing to do with that case.
You just need
to properly
persuade the Grand Commander.
Then your Yan family
could receive two
marriage contracts bestowed by the Grand Empress Dowager.
That would bring such great honor to your ancestors
and glory to your family name.
What were you hesitating about?
Why didn't you
agree immediately just now?
Princess Yong'an and Lord Lai
clearly don't want
the Imperial Security Bureau and the Ministry of Justice to be involved in this case.
But the more they act like this,
the more guilty they seem, don't they?
And logically speaking,
Princess Yong'an
has just been cleared of suspicion
in the Buddha's Sin-Absolving case.
So why is she in such a hurry
to wade into these troubled waters?
Xing,
this is clearly a bloody pit.
We should be running away from it,
you're not really thinking of jumping in, are you?
Chuichui...
Yan Xing!
You are the wife of the Grand Commander.
I can't control what trouble you're getting into.
But don't you dare
involve the Ministry of Justice
in this matter in any way.
The Ministry of Justice
won't go down with you.
Director.
Her Majesty's close confidant,
Zhang Baohuan, Deputy Minister,
has just alighted from his sedan chair outside the Ministry of Justice.
He says
he requests to speak with Miss Yan.
My Lady,
don't bring me
all these troubles.
Our Ministry of Justice is too small to handle this.
Lord Yan.
I know you are busy,
but I hope you don't mind
me visiting today.
I wouldn't dare to mind, sir.
The reason for my visit today
is not for any major inquiry.
I just wanted to ask
how Han Shiyuan has been
doing recently.
Mr. Han
returned to the Yan's Mansion with my third sister last night.
The Imperial Security Bureau didn't give him any trouble.
I went to the Yan's Mansion today,
but was told he wasn't there.
It seems
he still doesn't want to see me.
May I ask what connection you have
with Mr. Han?
It's nothing,
we're just old acquaintances.
Since Han Shiyuan
has won the favor of the Yan family's Third Miss,
it's his good fortune.
In the future,
if you have the chance, please
look after him in your household.
Of course.
Well then,
I won't disturb you any longer.
I'll take my leave now.
Han Shiyuan is very secretive about his relationship
with Zhang Baohuan
and Princess Yong'an.
Behind Chen Huo'e's resurrection,
there seem to be many forces involved.
It even involves
my third sister's marriage.
Even Lai Luozhi wants to interfere in this matter.
Now,
it seems everyone wants
me to stay out of it.
What should I do?
[Yan's Mansion]
Xing, you're here.
Sister Caiwei.
Mr. Han.
I should thank
you and the Grand Commander for last night.
Why did you specially bring gifts today?
Mrs. Shen,
I'm afraid you're here to interrogate us.
About last night's incident,
Shiyuan and I
really don't know anything.
Don't worry, Sister Caiwei.
The case from last night
will surely come to light.
I just want to know,
Mr. Han,
about you, Deputy Minister Zhang, and Princess Yong'an,
what's the relationship between the three of you?
I can't tell you.
At a time like this,
you still can't tell me?
If it weren't for you,
how could my sister
suffer so much?
Don't pressure Shiyuan anymore.
I believe him.
Xing, you're back.
Mother.
Don't you have to be on duty today?
You must be worried about those gifts,
wanting to go
to your third sister's place to check,
right?
Let me tell you,
this time, your husband
has done a very thorough job.
I'm also
riding on the coattails.
Gift?
Sister Caiwei just mentioned sending gifts.
What on earth are you talking about?
Don't you know?
This morning, the Shen family sent someone to express their concern.
They said you were worried that your third sister
was frightened last night.
They specially sent
a bunch of tonic gifts.
I could tell from the lavish gesture
that
it must have been paid for by my son-in-law.
Oh, right,
the kitchen is stewing some tonics.
Let's go.
I'll get you a bowl.
Shen Du.
I can't believe he did all this behind my back.
Why would he suddenly be so enthusiastic
about our family?
Isn't it obvious?
It must be because of you.
Otherwise, why would the Grand Commander
care about the small Yan family?
That stinky boy.
Does he still have ulterior motives,
pining for your third sister?
Your third sister
is the talented lady of Xiang'an after all.
She does seem more
desirable than you.
No, no,
this tendency
must be nipped in the bud.
I'll go persuade your father tonight
to quickly arrange
the marriage between Caiwei and Han Shiyuan.
We need to make sure they
seal the deal as soon as possible.
Mother,
what are you always
thinking about?
Has that White Ghost
been hitting you recently?
Have you two been arguing lately?
Let me tell you,
you can't let your guard down.
You must keep a close eye on him,
and never slack off.
Alright, Mother, I understand.
I'm suddenly feeling a bit hungry.
Why don't you go get me a bowl of soup?
I almost forgot again.
Wait here.
[Reviving Elegant Music]
What a fine zither.
What a beautiful melody.
Such wonderful artistic conception.
The piece Jin Zang played today
seems different from before.
It has a touch of Zen to it,
making one feel refreshed upon hearing it.
This is an ancient elegant music
Palace Steward Xu found.
When I visited the temple to pay respects to Buddha a few days ago,
a senior monk gifted me a musical score.
It's said to have the effect of clearing the mind.
So I asked Musician Jin
to play it elegantly.
Indeed, it's marvelous.
I remember
back then,
you personally went up the mountain to dig lingzhi mushrooms
and gave them to me,
asking me to treat the Shen family's case leniently
and give a lighter sentence,
releasing young Shen Du from prison.
So today,
what is your request?
I wouldn't dare, Your Majesty.
Summon him in then.
Mr. Shen,
I know why you're here.
Lord Lai
requested a retrial of Chen Huo'e's case.
This case,
although recently investigated by you,
was after all handled by him
five years ago.
He admits his negligence
and now wishes to make amends for his mistakes.
It's only human nature.
Your Majesty.
I believe
the dead cannot be brought back to life.
The Chen Huo'e from back then
may not be the same as the recent Chen Huo'e.
Mr. Shen,
since you're unwell,
there's no need to force yourself.
It's just a minor injury.
I've already recovered.
Very well.
Since Palace Steward Xu has vouched for you,
the Chen Huo'e case
will be handed over to the Imperial Security Bureau for investigation.
Yes, Your Majesty.
In that case,
the matter concerning the Hongwen Academy scholars
will be handled by Prime Minister Zhang.
After all, he is a civil official
and will find it easier
to communicate with the scholars.
Mr. Shen,
you will be responsible for the recent security of the capital.
How does that sound?
Your Majesty.
The security of the capital is of utmost importance.
We cannot afford any mistakes.
The Imperial Security Bureau is short-staffed.
I'm afraid it will be difficult to ensure comprehensive protection.
You clever monkey!
Usually, you only complain about not having enough power.
But today,
you're making excuses.
Do you think I
don't know what you're thinking?
I wouldn't dare, Your Majesty.
Wouldn't dare?
I think you're all plotting against me.
You've got some nerve!
-Your Majesty, please calm down.
-Your Majesty. Please forgive me.
Enough, enough.
Since I've entrusted you with the capital's security,
I will naturally give you
the authority to mobilize resources from various places.
During the examination period at the Hongwen Academy,
for all matters related to security,
personnel from all regions
will be at your disposal.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Your Highness,
Prime Minister Zhang has already taken control of the Hongwen Academy.
That old bastard.
He has gotten ahead of us again.
Now this is interesting.
Your Highness.
Mentor.
You've come at the perfect time.
Take a look at my Imperial Yellow Peony.
Isn't it blooming beautifully?
Yes, it's beautiful.
Your Highness,
this time, Her Majesty
allows me to handle
the matter of the Hongwen Academy examination.
These scholars of the Hongwen Academy
are the finest students in the land.
With their achievements in this examination,
Your Highness
will have a higher chance
of obtaining the position of Regent.
Mentor,
whether it's I
or Princess Ying who becomes Regent in the future,
we are all serving
Her Majesty and His Majesty.
Your Highness, I must respectfully disagree with your statement.
His Majesty is slow of speech,
Her Majesty is advanced in years,
and the Regent
is of utmost importance to the foundation of the Cang State.
In this matter,
Your Highness must not be negligent.
Mentor, you have worked hard on this.
It's crucial to correct everyone's misunderstandings
and make the vast number of scholars from humble backgrounds
feel
our genuine care and respect for them.
Yes, yes, indeed.
That is natural.
However,
this time Shen Du has again been given
the responsibility for the capital's security,
gaining additional authority without reason.
Lord Shen is indeed capable.
No matter what kind of situation
this person encounters,
or what kind of trouble arises,
he always has a way to deal with it.
Mentor,
what do you think?
Your Highness is right.
As for this Shen Du,
now that he's in charge of the capital's security,
shouldn't the situation in Xiang'an
be
more chaotic and lively?
Your Highness,
should we lend him a hand?
What did you just say?
You may go now.
Grand Commander.
The responsibility for the imperial examination at Hongwen Academy
has ultimately been entrusted to Prime Minister Zhang.
Her Majesty has assigned the security of the capital
to the Imperial Security Bureau.
Is this meant as a gesture of appeasement?
This is precisely the outcome I desired.
You don't seem disappointed at all.
A storm is brewing.
During the imperial examination at Hongwen Academy,
Princess Ying, Prince Xian,
Prime Minister Zhang, and Lai Luozhi will surely
make their moves.
Keep a close eye on them.
Yes.
The security around Hongwen Academy
cannot be underestimated.
We can deploy
the Imperial Guards and the constables to assist.
Also, the security of the Three Departments and Six Ministries
cannot be overlooked.
The Imperial Security Bureau will personally keep a close watch.
Especially...
on Lintai.
Understood.
Who is it?
Grand Commander Shen.
Thank you for the gifts
you sent to my third sister and the others.
They all loved them.
It's nothing.
At today's court session,
was there anything interesting?
Nothing much,
except Lai Luozhi came
to request the authority to investigate the Chen Huo'e case.
Did Her Majesty grant it to him?
She gave it to me.
You...
You mean the Chen Huo'e case
will still be handled by the Imperial Security Bureau?
That's great!
I'll go grind some ink for you.
No matter how you tidy up a doghouse,
it's still a doghouse.
How's
your hand?
It was bitten by a puppy.
It won't heal that quickly.
Grand Commander Shen.
Take a look at the case files.
Take a break.
Would you like me to cook for you?
You know how to cook?
Don't underestimate me.
I am the great Yan Xing after all.
Yes.
A talent for poetry.
Your writing is like a dance, depicting phoenixes with grace.
You're well-versed in classics and contemporary knowledge.
Your reputation as a virtuous lady
is unmatched in Xiang'an...
Let's go.
Hurry.
Please, have a seat.
Grand Commander.
I cooked all these dishes myself.
Please try them.
Try this chicken.
How is it?
Surprisingly,
it's not bad.
See? See?
I told you,
the principles of cooking and autopsy
are quite similar.
Using preservation
and autopsy techniques
to process this chicken
results in a texture
just like freshly slaughtered chicken.
Right.
Try this soup now.
The inspiration for these spices
comes from
Mrs. Tang's corpse-pickling spices.
Take a whiff.
Isn't the aroma overwhelming?
Isn't it?
Smells good, right?
What do you want?
Just say it.
I've succeeded so quickly?
I wanted to say...
Can I be involved in
Chen Huo'e's case?
No.
Can't you see
how complicated this case is?
The Ministry of Justice and the Court of Judicial Review
are both trying to avoid it at all costs.
And here you are, asking to be involved.
I know.
Lai Luozhi and Princess Yong'an
both came to see me today.
Directly and indirectly,
they just don't want me
to get involved in this case.
But I'm just
a lowly scribe.
Are they really afraid of me?
What they're afraid of
is just my title as Mrs. Shen.
Since you already know.
You've already taken on this case.
Now,
I can't escape my role
as Mrs. Shen.
How can I stay
completely uninvolved?
If you encounter danger,
how can I stay out of it?
I apologize.
There's nothing to apologize for.
Uncovering the truth
and clearing people's names
has always been my ideal.
I only ask
that you give me
the authority to investigate.
Don't worry,
I absolutely won't hold you back.
I won't become a burden to you either.
[Imperial Security Bureau]
But you have to promise me first.
in this case,
if anything happens,
you must consult with me
before making any decisions.
Do not act on your own under any circumstances.
Of course.
You are the Grand Commander,
my superior.
Naturally, I'll follow your instructions.
From now on,
I will obey only the Grand Commander's orders.
Is that alright?
Nonsense.
[Imperial Security Bureau]
[Chen's Mansion]
The Imperial Security Bureau is investigating a case.
Is Lord Chen Shoujie here?
I am Yan Xing, a scribe from the Ministry of Justice.
I have a few questions for him.
That night, the madam was in a good mood.
She personally cooked,
making water-boiled mutton and smoked chicken.
She also baked flatbread and pilaf.
She even rewarded this old servant with a bowl of wine.
I was sleeping until midnight
when I suddenly heard
the master's screams.
Honey!
As a result, the madam...
[Chen Shoujie]
My Lord.
Be careful.
[Jinxiu Workshop]
Master! Master!
-Master!
-Fire!
Master, master!
There's a fire!
Master!
-Master!
-E.
It's on fire, master!
-Fire!
-Master!
E... E...
Could he be referring to Chen Huo'e?
[Ministry of Justice]
Don't get close to everyone.
From now on, you'll sit
here.
Since you're working cases for the Imperial Security Bureau,
you'll no longer have anything
to do with the Ministry of Justice.
No matter how much trouble you cause,
it has nothing to do with the Ministry of Justice.
We at the Ministry of Justice
won't wade into these murky waters.
We won't.
Yan Xing.
Let me tell you,
no matter what,
at any time,
you must protect yourself.
If you die,
I will definitely...
I will definitely arrange performances in Furong Garden
for three days straight,
so you won't rest in peace even after death.
Don't worry,
I won't let you have your way.
In the third year of Shengli,
Jinxiu Workshop was accused of treason
summer clothes that exceeded regulations to Princess Runing,
[Case File of Jinxiu Workshop]
committed the crime of insubordination.
As the summer clothes were ordered by the Prince Consort,
[Princess Runing]
Runing's Prince Consort committed suicide in court to atone for the crime.
Since then, Princess Runing
has been at odds with the current Grand Empress Dowager.
As for Jinxiu Workshop,
due to the use of patterns that exceeded regulations,
they committed a grave offense against the royal family and were shut down.
The family of the Jinxiu Workshop owner was executed.
This is known as the Jinxiu Workshop case.
[Jinxiu Workshop]
Overruled?
[Case File of Jinxiu Workshop]
Rumors have it that four years ago,
the Prince Consort wanted to show his merits and present a treasure.
Unexpectedly, it led Princess Runing
to mistakenly wear the same
purple chrysanthemum patterned attire as the late Empress.
This angered
the current Grand Empress Dowager.
But in this file,
they only dared to vaguely write it as "exceeding the regulations."
It's clear that the case files can't be fully trusted.
Come and take a look at the pancakes.
Come.
-Mr. Pan.
I never expected to find someone of your talent here.
You've made it easy for us to find you.
And you two are?
The other day at the Hongwen Academy,
I witnessed your quick wit.
I heard
that you're also taking the Hongwen Academy exam.
In the future,
we'll be fellow students.
I’m flattered.
-Let’s go.
-I’m flattered.
We must have a drink.
-Let’s go.
Okay.
-This way, please.
After you, Mr. Pan.
Good, good, good.
This is by the order of Prince Xian and Prime Minister Zhang.
They value and cherish talent.
They specifically instructed us
to interact with the scholars from humble backgrounds who are taking the exam
and exchange ideas with them.
So that in the future, we can better
serve the court.
This talented scholar,
please, have a seat.
Please, sit down. No need for formalities.
His Majesty is benevolent.
This Hongwen Academy examination
disregards family background,
ignores social status,
doesn't require recommendations,
and judges solely on virtue and talent.
It can be said to set a precedent for our dynasty,
truly a blessing for scholars.
Indeed.
I have been ordered by Prime Minister Zhang
to prepare some modest wine for your reception.
All you students of the Hongwen Academy,
please take this opportunity
to interact more with these talented scholars.
Come on.
Please.
Come on. A toast to everyone.
What is the meaning of this?
Prince Xian
has always cherished scholars,
fearing that you students
might find your daily life in Xiang'an
not quite convenient.
He has specially sent someone to deliver this modest gift.
Gentlemen,
do you see Prince Xian's
benevolence and virtue?
Gentlemen,
please do accept it.
So this is the sincerity of your noble class.
Mr. Pan.
He dares to disrespect Prime Minister Zhang?
He doesn't know what's good for him.
The rich feast while the poor starve.
Using such despicable means
to bribe and corrupt people's hearts.
You poor boy,
don't refuse the easy way and choose the hard way.
You're Prime Minister Zhang's men?
If bribery fails, you resort to violence.
How dare you say that?
How dare you?
Xiang'an City
is right under the Emperor's nose,
You'd better soften your knees.
That way, you'll suffer less.
Be smart about this.
And who are you people?
Prime Minister Zhang shows womanly mercy,
but Prince Xian is wise.
You poor, pathetic scholars,
threats and bribes won't work on you.
You'd better be killed.
We just don't want to serve
under Prime Minister Zhang and Prince Xian.
Does that mean we have to be silenced?
Kill them!
Prince Xian won't let you off.
Hya!
It's you.
Grand Commander Shen.
Watch out!
[Guanyin Hall]
This person's hidden strength is formidable.
The force of his concealed weapons is powerful and vicious.
Be careful.
Yes.
After them!
Hurry!
Your Highness.
I don't know who
pinned this note to the corridor pillar.
[Tonight, the poor family is destroyed]